MANDIP GIRI

BASIC INFORMATION

Lalitpur Kathmandu mandipgiri@hotmail.com, +977 984 945 0329

Website: mandipgiri.com.np

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/mandip-giri-02166080

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Competent, hard working professional who can work under pressure and loves to face new challenges who has been in the industry for more than 6 years with speciality in **React** and **React Native**. **Highly motivated** and **enthused** individual with proper communication skills to be a **team player**.

A programming / technology enthusiast who is always ready to learn and grow.

EDUCATION

Higher Secondary Level (+2) in Science
Prasadi Academy

Bachelor's in Computer Engineering

2017

2011

Kantipur Engineering College

SKILLS

Schooling

- Javascript
- Typescript
- React
- React Native
- Redux with middlewares like Redux Saga/Redux Thunk
- Node JS
- Express JS
- AWS Services
- Android App Development (Java / Kotlin)

WORK EXPERIENCE

Android Internship Oct 2017 - Dec 2017

Hazesoft Pvt. Ltd

Learned about android development processes and its architecture, software development life cycles in a real world project

This resume is made with CVwizard.com.

Mobile App Developer

Jan 2018 - July 2019

Hazesoft Pvt. Ltd

I was employed at Hazesoft as an mobile app developer (Android Native App developer/ React Native Developer). I had been developing React Native App in Hazesoft since Dec,2018 alongside Android Native Apps.My core responsibility is to look over all the current projects app-side, upgrade them with new technologies and features as required and fix bugs if any arises. I have previously worked at Hazesoft as a Junior Android Developer for approximately 4 months ,where I had delivered two apps in Java , in co ordinance with my Senior developers.

Application Engineer July 2019 – Jun 2023

AMNIL Technologies

As an Application Engineer at AMNIL Technologies was to develop mobile applications with **React Native** along with providing support to previous projects for feature enhancements and issue fixes. Also from time to time I provided support to frontend team on React JS projects and also mentor interns for React. As for my recent role for last project I have been doing Team Lead & Application Engineer where I was managing my team member's along with communicating with the client and closing communication gap with the team and client. Understand the requirement of the client and see that the team understands it and get it done.

Software Engineer Jan 2022 - Jul 2023

Cloudfactory

As a Software Engineer at Cloudfactory, I had been working as a fullstack developer for a internal tool of the company. I had been working to develop features along with understanding domains. I had been grooming myself to new tech stack that included **React** with **NodeJS** in **BFF** pattern followed by **Golang** and **AWS**. In this time I also had mentored interns.

During this time I was fortunate enough to have presented in **JS community** named **KTMJS** on **React Testing Library**.

Senior Software Engineer

Jul 2023 - Current

Cloudfactory

I am continuing the same work I did as a Software Engineer but now I get more involved in technical and architecture decisions. Since I have nieche experience in React, I help other team members and lead different improvements and try to drive and set standards for React and help them introduce to new tech in React itself.

PROJECTS WORKED ON

Android Native Projects:

Hayn Customer App
Hayn Provider App
Lugmety Customer App
Lugmety Driver App
Lugmety Restaurant App
Albagal
Dokaan
Yummy
Lugmety Driver App v2
Lugmety Customer App

React-Native Projects:

HR PIE
DishHome Care
cdmSmith
ePharmacy Nepal
Nagarik News

This resume is made with CVwizard.com.

Hamro Nirman Mamut ERP (Magro) Vesta Home Vesta Partner

Personal Projects:

e commerce using React JS and firebase - https://omg-clothing.herokuapp.com/ Covid Tracking with MERN stack - https://covid19-mern.herokuapp.com/ portfolio using NEXTJS and Tailwind CSS - https://www.mandipgiri.com.np/

College Projects

Project Aider - We developed web application for repository and project and task collaboration using Java for final year project.

Restaurant Management System - We built a desktop app using Java platform which managed the employee records, menus and calculated bills. The app also showed graph of most sold food items for minor project.

Departmental Billing System -We designed a system for calculating the bills for a supermarket using C++. Hotel Management System - We designed a system that reserved the room and calculated the total bill of the customer using C.

INTERESTS

Coding
Learning new technologies/languages in programming
Cooking
Music

REFERENCES

- Er.Dipesh Shrestha Project Assistant, Kantipur Engineering College, Dhapakhel, Lalitpur
- Mr. Bijay Luitel CTO, Hazesoft Pvt. Ltd
- Mr. Niroj Maharjan Sr. Android Developer
- Mr. Bedh Raj Dhakal Software Engineer
- Mr. Chewang Yolmoo Senior Software Engineer
- Mr. Yuba Raj Oli Application Engineer
- Mr. Mahan Adhikari Senior Software Engineer
- Mr. Sunil Poudel Senior Software Engineer
- Mr. Samit Ghimire Lead Engineer